# LAURENT NTIBARIKURE

## **Engineering Systems | Physical Modeling | Customer Focus**

ntilau.github.io

in ntilau

ntilau

Findhoven, Netherlands

# **SUMMARY**

My experiences, with a focus on numerical methods, encompass electronic and mechatronic system development and technical sales & support across several industries (Energy & Aerospace, Electronic Design Automation, and Semiconductors).

Leveraging such a background, I am currently helping designers to develop more effectively towards system-level compliance.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Sr Engineer - Design Enablement

#### **NXP Semiconductors**

🗂 03/2022 - Present

Eindhoven, Netherlands

- Implemented electromagnetic simulation flows for SoCs development and electromagnetic interference predictions.
- Enhanced vendor solutions to meet the design and integration requirements of the cloud platform.
- Developed problem-resolution automation scripts and applied AI/ML algorithms for electromagnetic surrogate models.

#### **Technical Account Manager**

#### **Ansys**

- Utrecht, Netherlands
- Drove customer satisfaction by providing multi-disciplinary technical support and managing global presales activities for the Ansys portfolio.
- Led teams to architect flows across disciplines, focusing on requirements and critical success factors.
- Advised global sales and account engineers on addressable initiatives and pipelines with preliminary requirements and solutions visions.

#### Sr. Applications Engineer

## **Ansys**

- Utrecht, Netherlands
- Executed presales activities for electronic systems across industries, supporting high frequency solutions and EMC flows across EMEA.
- · Led technical alignment with customers on automotive electrification and connectivity projects, successfully delivering consulting services and trainings.

#### Lead Engineer - Testing

#### **Baker Hughes**

**□** 06/2013 - 12/2018

- Florence, Italy
- Led the development of industrial, ATEX compliant, distributed data acquisition systems to streamline tests execution timelines from months to weeks.
- Resolved 5+ electromagnetic interference issues in NPI validations and factory acceptance tests, contributing to best practices.
- Received an innovation award for patent disclosure of the Structural Vibration Monitoring System and multiple rewards for innovative solutions and customer impact.

# Startup Co-founder

# Università degli Studi di Firenze

**Ö** 06/2012 − 06/2013

- Florence, Italy
- Initiated a spin-off, ElectroSoft, to provide efficient numerical codes for design problems.

## **EDUCATION**

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Electronics Engineering

#### Università degli Studi di Firenze

School of "RF, Microwaves and Electromagnetics". Computational Methods focus. With grant (Jan 2011 - Jun 2013).

# Master's Degree, Electronics Engineering

#### Università degli Studi di Firenze

☐ 10/2007 - 04/2010 Florence, Italy

Erasmus Placement/LLP framework thesis semester at Universität des Saarlandes. With grant (Sep 2009 - Mar 2010).

# Bachelor's degree, Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Università degli Studi di Firenze

# **AWARDS**

### EMEA TAM of the Year | Ansys (01/2021)

Award for customer and industry focus

Learn and adapt to win | BHGE (07/2018)

Patent impact award for the disclosure of "Module with sensors arrangement"

Customers determine our success | BHGE (03/2017)

> Bronze award for the GE Aviation's Catalyst FETT advanced test instrumentation consulting

Customers determine our success | GE (10/2016)

Bronze award for the successful execution of the vibration monitoring system **ZADCO** customer structural vibrations acceptance tests

Learn and adapt to win | GE (03/2016) Bronze award for the co-generation plant cost savings on the SNC1-2 steam turbine performance validation

Learn and adapt to win | GE (10/2015) Bronze award for the introduction and validation of an effective, cost-saving, structural vibrations digital integration algorithm aimed at accurately deriving

speed & displacements measurements from ATEX-compliant accelerometers

External focus | GE (06/2014) • Led team promotion and value proposition pitches to business angels. Bronze award for the RCA activities on • Developed first opportunities in the defense industry. Cessao Onerosa, ADRE monitoring system EMI noise mitigation and customer assurance **Doctoral Researcher** Università degli Studi di Firenze Giorgio Barzilai Prize | SIEm (09/2012) **□** 01/2011 - 06/2013 Florence, Italy Best paper award for young researchers, for the work "Model order reduction in • Researched applied & computational electromagnetics, presenting 10+ papers, advis-Finite Element analysis of phased array ing student theses, and supporting examinations. antennas" presented at the XIX RiNEm Developed high-frequency electromagnetics 3D finite element C++ code for domain decomposition and nonlinear formulations. Ph.D. studies grant | UniFi (12/2010) Architected a methodology using MathWorks Simulink and Ansys HFSS for electro-Full tuition fees and allowance for remagnetic compatibility in variable speed drive systems. search on Electromagnetic Compatibility modeling techniques in variable speed drive systems - with GE/Nuovo Pignone Visiting Researcher Universität des Saarlandes Dean's listing | UniFi (04/2010) **1**0/2009 - 02/2010 Commissione di Laurea Specialistica in In- Saarbrücken, Germany gegneria Elettronica presieduta dal Prof. • Developed model order reduction in finite element analysis of antenna arrays for fast Piero Tortoli (Prot. 1051 n. class. III/9.1.2 and accurate beamforming. del 24 Maggio 2010) • Implemented Matlab code for a 3000x matrix reduction and 300x speedup in antenna pattern computation LLP/Erasmus Placement grant | UniFI (10/2009)Thesis work semester relocation support **R&D** Engineer at Universität des Saarlandes Università degli Studi di Firenze **1**2/2007 - 03/2008 Florence, Italy CERTIFICATION • Developed wireless connectivity for a battery-powered avalanche rescue ground pen-Professional Engineer, etrating radar, optimizing firmware for fast full-duplex/half-duplex conversion timing. ID:ES2010277049000038 • Executed the design and assembly of an ISM 868 MHz serial modem PCB prototype Università degli Studi di Firenze with off-the-shelf MCU and Radio (sub-GHz RFFE). Achieved successful wireless system resulting in improved signal detection accuracy. **COURSES PROJECTS** Command of the Message Bearings loading test rig **Ansys** □ 06/2020 Remote Baker Hughes, a GE Company **Ö** 05/2018 - 12/2018 Florence, Italy JAWS: Just Another Way of Selling Conceptual design of a novel bearings loading test rig aimed at validating bearings **Ansvs**  □ 02/2020 Paris, France • Investigated on modeling methods of EM coupling between power (variable speed drive system) and signals cabling systems to predict potential interference issues. GE Crotonville: Delivering Customer Im-**GE** Aviation's Catalyst GE Oil & Gas Baker Hughes, a GE Company □ 03/2016 Munich, Germany Prague, Czech Republic Total Quality Lean Six Sigma Green Belt • Led special instrumentation design and global technical reviews of FETT with design **GE Oil & Gas** and testing teams (Czech Rep., Poland, USA, Canada). □ 06/2014 • Contributed to >4 M\$ corss-P&L project and customer satisfaction. Florence, Italy

## Gas Turbine embedded SAW sensors

#### Gas Turbine embedded SAVV sensor

Baker Hughes, a GE Company

□ 02/2018 - 12/2018

▼ Florence, Italy

• Collaborated with University of Florence to investigate the high-frequency numerical modeling of SAW sensors for the accuracy control of temperature measurements.

## LM9000: 65 MW aeroderivative gas turbine

Baker Hughes, a GE Company

□ 06/2018 - 12/2018

Florence, Italy

## **LANGUAGES**

Semiconductors

**SKILLS** 

Testing

Engineering

Sales

**Customer Satisfaction** 

Finite Element Analysis

Python

**Simulations** 

Strategy

Scripting

RF

Management

Leadership

Matlab

Electronics

 Contributed to conceptual instrumentation design and test rigs erection, data acquisition architecture and control system design by technical and HAZOP reviews. Dutch Cross'd **English Ö** 01/2018 - 11/2018 Florence, Italy French • Social networking app PoC based on Bluetooth Low Energy ranging. PoC with Apache Cordova and an AWS EC2 instance German **BLE Asset Tracking** Italian **Ö** 07/2017 - 09/2017 Florence, Italy Sub 5\$/Unit PoC of BLE tags (TI's CC2640) with firmware optimized for long-battery Kirundi life, aimed at asset tracking and inventory management Spanish GE Power slip-ring digital telemetry **PUBLICATIONS** 

#### Universität des Saarlandes

**Ö** 04/2017 - 05/2017

Saarbrücken, Germany

- Ran Ansys HFSS simulations to optimize signal integrity over slip-ring connections (power supply and ethernet transmission lines)
- Achieved shrinking of the rings spacing leading to manufacturing costs reduction
- 4 weeks-FTE cross-P&L billing and customer satisfaction

# Wet gas compressors at KLAB

#### **GE Oil & Gas**

Haugesund, Norway

- Designed and procured validation equipment for ATEX zone 1 test bench.
- Developed Ex-d antenna and low noise amplifier system for GPS synchronization on NI's PXI systems.
- Managed IEC 60079-11 simple apparatus compliance on load cells upon using extremely low voltage (1.5 V) Ex-ia Wheatstone bridge conditioners.

#### Power density compressor

#### **GE Oil & Gas**

**Ö** 03/2014 - 05/2016

Florence, Italy

- Led the commissioning Fieldbus Foundation use in testing lab for more than 240 pressure transducers (0.1% uncertainty) upon identifing the proper Firmware configuration which enabled for massive and accurate pressure measurements.
- Managed capacitive vibration probes ATEX-compliance.
- Developed electrostatic numerical model to predict capacitance variation in various surroundings and target shape conditions.
- Contributed to DM37/08 compliance of the test rig contract specification, including power and signaling cabling selection and proper installation.

# SNC1-2 steam turbine performance evaluation in 6.2 MW cogeneration plant **GE Oil & Gas**

**Ö** 09/2015 - 04/2016

Florence, Italy

- Defined novel pressure hookups method at lower cost and better performance to achieve accuracy controlled inter-stage enthalpy measurements according to ASME PTC 19.11.
- Programmed a CAN to Modbus TCP embedded module to enable static torque measurements on a MagCanica telemetry.

# GE-6G PowerGen Module Structural Vibrations Monitoring System

# **GE Oil & Gas**

**11/2015 - 03/2016** 

Saarbrücken, Germany

# US20180180464A1/en.

Books

Patents

· L. Ntibarikure, Contributions to the Art of Finite Elements in Electromagnetics. Florence, Italy, 2014. [Online]. Available: https://hdl. handle.net/2158/843133.

• L. Ntibarikure, "Module with sensors ar-

rangement," US20180180464A1. [Online]. Available: https://patents.google.com/patent/

## Journal Articles

- L. Ntibarikure, "Multiphysics simulations for 5g rfics and socs," Bits&Chips, 2019.
- F. Barone, A. Signorini, L. Ntibarikure, T. Fiore, F. Di Pasquale, and C. J. Oton, "Fiberoptic liquid level sensing by temperature profiling with an fbg array," Sensors, vol. 18, no. 8, 2018. [Online]. Available: https:// www.mdpi.com/1424-8220/18/8/2422.
- L. Ntibarikure, G. Pelosi, and S. S. and, "Harmonic balance domain decomposition finite elements for nonlinear passive microwave devices analysis," Electromagnetics, vol. 34, no. 3-4, pp. 239-252, 2014. DOI: 10.1080/02726343.2014.877756.
- L. Ntibarikure, G. Pelosi, and S. Selleri, "Efficient harmonic balance analysis of waveguide devices with nonlinear dielectrics," **IEEE Microwave and Wireless Components** Letters, vol. 22, no. 5, pp. 221-223, 2012. DOI: 10.1109/LMWC.2012.2192420.

# Conference Proceedings

• L. Ntibarikure, G. Pelosi, and S. Selleri, "Assessment of the performances of gmres(r) using a domain decomposition approach as a preconditioner," in Proceedings, XX Riunione Nazionale di Elettromagnetismo (XX RiNEm), Padua, Italy, 2014. [Online]. Available: https: //inspirehep.net/literature/1403858.

Project involving ATEX-compliant distributed acquisition system for more than 150 vibration measurement points, with 40 kHz analog bandwidth, WiFi5 backhaul to storage and real-time monitoring, GPS or daisy-chain clock distribution synchronization & TSN investigation, characterized of 3D models & BOM detailed design re-insourcing for timely delivery and cost optimization of certified equipment in less than 4 months (vs typ. 8 months). This also led to the introduction and consolidation of a software based velocity and displacement real-time computation from accelerometers, achieving direct \$150k savings, and subsequent lab processes OPEX improvements. Customer value delivered as onsite Turbomachinery Modules structural commissioning.

 L. Ntibarikure, "Model order reduction in finite elements analysis of phased array antennas," in Proceedings, XIX Riunione Nazionale di Elettromagnetismo (XIX RiNEm), S. d. E. SiEm, Ed., Roma, Italy, 2012.

L. Ntibarikure, G. Pelosi, and S. Selleri, "Harmonic balance finite element analysis of third order intermodulation products in ferrite devices," in *Proceedings, XIX Riunione Nazionale di Elettromagnetismo (XIX RiNEm)*, S. d. E. SiEm, Ed., Roma, Italy, 2012.

# NovaLT16 gas turbine, bearings and cooling component tests

#### **GE Oil & Gas**

**Ö** 04/2014 - 10/2015

- Saarbrücken, Germany
- Design and validation of smartbox (field datalogger) for analog signals.
- Defined EMC-aware measurement loops design to achieve noise immunity and enhanced measurement accuracies, rigorously applying EN 61000 guidelines (CENELEC 25).

# GE Aviation's GE9X High Pressure Compressor

#### **GE Oil & Gas**

**Ö** 01/2014 - 04/2014

- Massa, Italy
- High density data acquisition system design for GE Aviation's compressor test in Massa.
- Performed mitigation on EMC noise due to 130 kW variable speed ventilation system

#### BCL306 and BCL317 centrifugal compressors rotordynamics

## **GE Oil & Gas**

□ 06/2013 - 03/2014

▼ Florence, Italy

 Performed an Ex-p execution of stability's magnetic exciter, contributed to the resolution of customer's opened nonconformity on rotordynamic vibrations upon conducting an electromagnetic interference on Bently Nevada's 3500 RCA.

# Finite Elements Software (FES)

# Università degli Studi di Firenze

▼ Florence, Italy

 FES is an open source C++ framework for the development of "ad-hoc" simulation software aimed at a rapid implementation of novel numerical methods based on the Galerkin method. Core formulations validated reusing meshes from commercial packages (Comsol, HFSS)

# Spectral domain FEM model order reduction

## Universität des Saarlandes

**1**0/2009 - 02/2010

- Saarbrücken, Germany
- Developed in Matlab efficient near-to-far-fields formulations for fast electromagnetic radiation computation in large finite elements problems exploiting model order reduction with spectral interpolation for beam steering and pattern angles
- Modeled a large patch antenna array, assessing accuracy and performances through mesh/model export from Ansoft HFSS v11  $\,$

#### RS-232 modem in ISM 868 MHz band

#### **University of Florence**

**1** 01/2007 - 04/2007

- ♥ Florence, Italy
- Designed and prototyped an 868 MHz wireless link for a ground penetration radar remote control over RS-232 protocol
- C-coded the PIC microcontroller FW and optimized in Assembly to garantee the fullduplex operation over half-duplex TI's CC1100 radio.
- Evaluated the performance of the wireless link in open field